

Amanuel Tesfay

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

+251914131366 amanueltesfay99@gmail.com https://www.amanueltesfay.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/am anuel-tesfay-576b121a2/

ABOUT ME

I am an Energetic Operations Support with more than 4 years of experience resolving complex customer inquiries. Passionate about building strong customer relationships, driving brand loyalty, and increasing customer engagement I am highly motivated to continue learning and improving my craft.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- · Problem-solving.
- · Team working skills, Active listening
- · Customer Service Skills.
- Communication
- · Time management
- Proficient in using freshdesk and atlassian jira software

CERTIFICATION & VOLUNTEER WORK

Full-stack developer Evangadi Networks 2022

Online courses provided by Evangadi Networks covered HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, media-query, Javascript, Node.Js, React.Js, Mysql, Git, Git-hub, and express.Js with projects.

Microsoft talent training Certificate Gebeya Talent agency 2021

The online program provided by Microsoft company covered C#, JAVA, and DevOps and how to build an inbound marketing strategy.

Volunteer Administrator Zewditu Meshesha (philanthropist)

Collaborated with a team of 15+ volunteers to raise funds, and support kids who lost their parents.

WORK HISTORY

Junior Software Engineer

Paga payment

January 2023 to Present

- Assisting the development manager with all aspects of software design and coding.
- Attending and contributing to company development meetings.
- Learning the codebase and improving your coding skills.
- · Writing and maintaining code.
- Working on minor bug fixes.
- Monitoring the technical performance of internal systems.
- Responding to requests from the development team.
- Gathering information from consumers about program functionality.
- · Writing reports.
- · Conducting development tests.

Intern Software Engineer

Paga payment

August 2022 to Janury

- · Developing applications (coding, programming)
- Debugging and testing code
- Documenting and testing new software applications
- · Researching, investigating, and fixing a wide range of technical issues
- Collaborating with senior leaders
- Approaching problems and creating solutions
- Proactively learning about new technologies

Operations Support (Customer Experience)

Paga payment

September 2021 to August

- Ensure the delivery of excellent customer service when assisting customers and agents in a professional and efficient manner.
- Receive and respond to emails from customers and agents using applications like Freshdesk.
- Identifying and escalating priority issues to the appropriate quarters for assistance.

Customer Support Specialist

Apposit

February 2019 to September 2021

- Responsible for taking control of and resolving complex and escalated customer-related issues.
- Manages testing communications for all project work assigned, and documents and manages project issues.
- Works closely with software developers and support teams to foster high customer satisfaction and generate profit.

WORK HISTORY

Network administrator

Sheba University Collage January 2019 to March 2019

- Maintaining existing software and hardware and upgrading any that have become obsolete.
- Monitoring computer networks and systems to identify how performance can be improved.
- working with IT support personnel.
- Identifying and solving any problems that arise with computer networks and systems.
- Consulting with clients to specify system requirements and design solutions. Budgeting for equipment and assembly costs.

LANGUAGE & SOFTWARE SKILLS

Tigrinya: NativeAmharic: FluentEnglish: Fluent

- OS Linux, Windows
- MS SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle
- · HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, media-query
- Javascript, Node.Js, React.Js, express.Js,
- java, java Springboot, C#, C++, PHP
- · Git-hub and Git.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Sheba University Collage

Ethiopia, Mekelle Bachelor's Degree in Computer sciences, with GPA 3.06 September 2014 - July 2018

Ayder secondary and preparatory school

Ethiopia, Mekelle Completed secondary and preparatory school September 2011 - July 2014

REFERENCES

Bethlehem Girma Project manager | excellerent +251932201043 | betyy.gi@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Fanuel Yemane Project Manager | Safaricom +251912619047| fanu236@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Hareg Embaye Project Manager | Paga +251962230124 | hareg.embaye65@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Mahfuz Bedru
Head, Faculty of Informatics
Save the Children | Sheba university college
+251914727689 | mafbefru@gmail.com
Mekelle, Ethiopia